so ya so I am Jia Peng
那個，我是 Jia Peng
so
那麼
actually my background is more different than your all
其實我的背景跟你們都不太一樣
my background is on the cloud engineer
我是做 cloud engineer 的
which is working on the infrastructure side lah
就是負責 infrastructure 這塊的啦
so basically what I'm doing for my job is
所以基本上我的工作就是
gathering the requirement from the clients to
從客戶那邊收集需求，然後
let's say they want to host
比如說他們要 host
how many server
幾臺 server
that are trying to design the network part
然後去設計 network 那部分
and also the
還有那個
traffic flow from the clients to the server
從客戶到 server 的 traffic flow（流量走向）
and then to calculating the costing of the resources
然後再計算這些 resources 的成本
also lah
也是要算的啦
so this is what I doing for my daily task
所以這就是我每天的工作
so actually
所以其實
I'm presenting on the AI meets infrastructure
我要講的是 AI meets infrastructure
which integrating the IaC AI agents and the markdown
就是把 IaC、AI agents 和 markdown 整合起來
I think do you guys like ever heard what is IaC before
我想問，你們之前有聽過 IaC 是什麼嗎
like IaC so
就是 IaC
for the to introduce what is IaC lah
先來介紹一下 IaC 是什麼啦
so IaC is the infrastructure as code
IaC 就是 infrastructure as code（基礎設施即程式碼）
so I think most people think that the cloud is like
我想大部分人以為 cloud 就是
using the for example
比如說用
like I using the Azure service to create the
像我用 Azure 的服務去建立
server inside there
裡面的 server
using the Azure portal to create the server
用 Azure portal 去建立 server
to create the network and so on right
去建立 network 等等，對吧
so actually we the IaC
但其實我們的 IaC
to using the code
是用程式碼
to deploy the infra resources inside the cloud
去在 cloud 裡部署 infra resources
ya so this is the IaC what IaC is lah
ya，這就是 IaC，IaC 就是這樣啦
my ex
我以前的
I will talk about the experience before the IaC Lah
我來講講用 IaC 之前的經驗啦
so actually for my currently
其實我現在
right in my current company
在我現在的公司
I am using I
我用的是
also
也是
actually using the Azure portal to create the resource
其實是用 Azure portal 去建立 resource
and so on so actually
等等，所以其實
my idea from the IaC is coming from my ex tech lead Lah
我對 IaC 的想法是來自我以前的 tech lead 啦
so I have going I have
所以我有去，我有
gathering with my ex tech lead
跟我以前的 tech lead 交流過
so my tech lead is talking
我的 tech lead 講到
we are talking about the IaC
我們聊到 IaC
to using the code to deploy the infra
用程式碼去部署 infra
but my tech lead was asking me like
但我的 tech lead 問我說
is it our company still
我們公司是不是還
got
有
try to use the IaC to deploy the resources and so on
有沒有用 IaC 去部署 resources 之類的
so my company don't have this IaC code
結果我們公司沒有這個 IaC code
to deploy the resources ah
去部署 resources 啊
so we also didn't like
我們也沒有
integrate with any AI to deploy the infra resources
整合任何 AI 去部署 infra resources
inside the cloud services
在 cloud services 裡面
so actually I'm thinking like
所以其實我在想
how do we use the AI on the infrastructure
我們要怎樣把 AI 用在 infrastructure 上
not only on the software and software code
不只是用在 software 和 software code 上
but also in the infrastructure level
而是也用在 infrastructure 這個層面
like the cloud services so
像是 cloud services 這樣
before the IaC and I actually
在用 IaC 之前，我其實
we are doing the manual provisioning
我們是做 manual provisioning（手動配置）
like we are scatter the requirements from the emails
就是把需求從 email 裡東收西收
tickets and then do the changes
還有 ticket，然後去做修改
like clicking in the portal
就是在 portal 裡面點
one by one to do the things
一個一個去做
and then when we do the documentation
然後當我們做 documentation 的時候
we're also trying to keep clicking the agent
我們也是要一直點那個
the website portal
網站的 portal
to see what is the settings on the portal itself
去看 portal 上的設定是什麼
so which is quite troublesome for this
所以這個蠻麻煩的
those this one
那些，這個
because you have to click one by one
因為你要一個一個去點
all the things together so after this right
全部一起，所以在這之後
so I'm thinking like what if we integrating the IaC
我就在想，如果我們把 IaC 整合起來呢
the markdown the markdown code
那個 markdown，markdown code
like the skills markdown
像是 skills markdown
and the agent markdown with the IaC
還有 agent markdown，跟 IaC 一起
so the first so my
所以第一，我的
idea is first we will creating the markdown
想法是，首先我們會建立 markdown
so we are gathering the requirements and then we
我們收集需求，然後我們
to write all the requirements inside the markdown files
把所有需求寫進 markdown 檔案裡
and then let the AI agent to read the markdown to see
然後讓 AI agent 去讀 markdown，看看
what is the requirement
需求是什麼
what is the specification for the server
server 的規格是什麼
for the network and so on
network 的等等
so we
所以我們
so the AI agent will read and then it will generate IaC
AI agent 讀了之後，就會生成 IaC
the infrastructure code inside the
就是 infrastructure code，在那個
inside the ID itself and then we are using the
在 IDE 裡面，然後我們用
IaC to
IaC 去
run some command to deploy the infrastructure
跑一些 command 去部署 infrastructure
inside the Azure or AWS
在 Azure 或 AWS 裡面
so after that right
所以之後
during when we
在我們
trying to deploy the infrastructure using the code
用程式碼去部署 infrastructure 的時候
right we do have some command to validate to plan to
我們是有一些 command 去 validate、plan、
scan all those things using the Terraform
用 Terraform 去 scan 那些東西
the IaC code that I using is a Terraform ah
我用的 IaC code 就是 Terraform 啊
so Terraform had provided some of these feature
Terraform 有提供這些功能
to deploy it and then finally
去部署，然後最後
we will just do the pull request because we can also
我們就做 pull request，因為我們也可以
push our infrastructure code
把我們的 infrastructure code push
to the Github repo or the Gitlab repo itself
到 GitHub repo 或 GitLab repo
so we also
所以我們也
my idea is like we also have a PR review the approval
我的想法是，我們也有 PR review、審批
then only we will apply it lah
然後才會去 apply 啦
when we doing the production
在做 production 的時候
because we can't simply like doing terraform apply
因為我們不能隨便就 terraform apply
then we just directly apply inside the production
然後直接就 apply 到 production
infrastructure like this
infrastructure，這樣
so
所以
we are also have some kind of the PR review to approve
我們也有某種 PR review 去審批
then only deploy to the production infrastructure Lah
然後才部署到 production infrastructure 啦
so
所以
let me show you what is the
我給你們看看那個
like how exactly looks like lah
實際上是長怎樣的啦
the P the in the how the IaC wait ah
那個 P，那個，IaC 怎樣，等一下啊
sorry let me maybe I need to do this sorry okay
不好意思，我可能要這樣做，不好意思，okay
so this is how I see looks like I'm sorry
所以這就是 IaC 看起來的樣子，不好意思
so I see looks like
IaC 看起來就是這樣
so currently I'm using the Terraform ah
目前我用的是 Terraform 啊
so actually I'm not sure the AWS has
其實我不確定 AWS 有沒有
AWS has its own infrastructure code things
AWS 有它自己的 infrastructure code 那種東西
the native service
原生的服務
but Azure itself has a native service called Bicep
但 Azure 本身有一個原生服務叫 Bicep
the Bicep is also like looks like this ah
Bicep 看起來也是像這樣啊
you have the code to define what is the require
你用程式碼去定義那個需求
what's the specification for your network
你的 network 規格是什麼
and also the server itself lah
還有 server 本身啦
so basically I will have the requirements in the
所以基本上我會把需求放在
this so I can like define what is the region
這裡，這樣我就可以定義 region 是什麼
the CIDR for my network
我的 network 的 CIDR
and then the subnet for my network
然後我的 network 的 subnet
and also the instance type
還有 instance type
the VM instance type
那個 VM 的 instance type
what we are using for the VM itself
我們 VM 用的是什麼
so basically you see the main.tf
所以基本上你看 main.tf
so this is the big code lah like how do you deploy the
這就是主要的程式碼啦，就是你怎樣部署那個
deploy the
部署那個
resources and then you can see there is a
resources，然後你可以看到有一
lot of things define inside here
大堆東西定義在這裡
so this is just a basic code on that
這只是基本的程式碼
then can also then we can try to deploy like this
然後我們也可以這樣去部署
so this can you see
所以這個，你們看得到嗎
yeah so this
yeah，這個
is the basic thing that we will do lah
就是我們會做的基本步驟啦
we will try to terraform plan first
我們會先 terraform plan
then you will terraform command
然後你會用 terraform command
you will read the coding that you
它會讀你寫的程式碼
that you do inside the code
你在程式碼裡寫的
then you will read after read
然後它讀了又讀
then you will come out the result say
然後它會給出結果，說
what is the things that you will create inside the AWS
你會在 AWS 裡建立什麼東西
or Azure so you can see there is a AWS subnet that
或 Azure，你可以看到有一個 AWS subnet
the additional subnet that I
就是我額外加的 subnet
create inside here
在這裡建立的
then you then you just see Lor or if let's say
然後你就看咯，或者比如說
I want to add this one
我要加這個
then this is the result that I want
那這就是我要的結果
then you only apply the Terraform
然後你才去 apply Terraform
apply the terraform plan
apply 那個 terraform plan
so you only create the resource inside there
這樣你才會在裡面建立 resource
so how do I integrate this with the AI markdown agent
那我怎樣把這個跟 AI markdown agent 整合呢
is I also got do my own
就是我也有做我自己的
actually also generated by the AI Lah
其實也是 AI 生成的啦
I also got do my own agents markdown Lah
我也有做我自己的 agents markdown 啦
but it's more simple markdown
但它是比較簡單的 markdown
because I only based on the markdown format and so on
因為我只是照 markdown 的格式那樣
not the coding background
不是 coding 那種背景
so I trying to learn of it
所以我在學這個
so actually in here right
所以其實在這裡
I trying to I trying to mention ah
我想要，我想要提到啊
like
就是
what is the main files that the AI agent need to read
AI agent 需要讀的主要檔案是什麼
the requirement.md the skills.md
就是 requirement.md、skills.md
and also the IaC file and the documentation files
還有 IaC 檔案和 documentation 檔案
then I also like define got
然後我也有定義
define some of the behaviour for the agents
定義 agents 的一些行為
be read the requirements before generating
就是在生成之前要先讀需求
or changing this
或者修改這個
IaC code and some of the like security concern
IaC code，還有一些 security 方面的考量
because we don't want like
因為我們不想
agent to mess up our infrastructure
agent 把我們的 infrastructure 搞亂
because it said it mess up our infrastructure
因為如果它把我們的 infrastructure 搞亂
then it will mess up all the production environment Lah
那它就會把整個 production environment 搞亂啦
so we will
所以我們會
we will some of the rules to avoid that ya so
我們設一些規則去避免這個，ya
we also do some of the rules Lah for
我們也設一些規則啦，給
the agent itself so this is for the behaviour lah
agent 本身，所以這是關於行為的啦
the for the agent's behaviour
就是 agent 的行為
this is what I'm thinking to use the agents to
這是我想用 agents 來做的
as a behaviour stuff and then
當作行為方面的東西，然後
we also have a skills here
我們這裡也有 skills
to define
去定義
what is the workflow that they need to follow
他們需要遵循的 workflow 是什麼
like for example
比如說
if let's say I want to create one more VM
假設我要多建立一臺 VM
virtual machine inside the
虛擬機器，在那個
inside the environment
在 environment 裡面
so I will define to base on the requirement
所以我會定義說，根據 requirement
MD to pass the infrastructure requirement
MD 去解析 infrastructure 的需求
to identify what is the required resources
去識別需要哪些 resources
then checking all the things
然後檢查所有東西
then only if only you can update the Terraform files
然後才可以更新 Terraform 檔案
then to update the environment variable
然後更新 environment variable
if there is new variables for it
如果有新的 variables
then update the documentation and so on
然後更新 documentation 等等
so this one is just do the automate process
所以這個就是做自動化的流程
to do whole flow use the AI agent to do the whole flow
用 AI agent 去做整個流程
including the documentation
包括 documentation
because we don't want to like
因為我們不想
doing it by myself
自己一個一個做
recording the documentation one by one by me
自己一個一個去記錄 documentation
so I using the AI is more faster lah when we
所以我用 AI 是比較快的啦，當我們
I when I do the documentation
當我做 documentation 的時候
so this is what I'm thinking for the skills
所以這是我對 skills 的想法
markdown Lah for the infrastructure
就是 skills markdown 啦，給 infrastructure 用
so for the requirement here I also got do
所以這個 requirement，我也有做
so this one I have define lah
這個我有定義啦
what is the requirement 1
就是 requirement 1 是什麼
requirement 2 but this one the requirement.md
requirement 2，但這個是 requirement.md
actually
其實
I trying to see if I can separate like for example
我在看能不能分開，比如說
what koha show is to by the by Fisher model
就像剛才那位展示的那種按模組分的方式
so maybe I can also like
所以也許我也可以
separating the requirement by requirement 1
把 requirement 分開，requirement 1
requirement 2 lah
requirement 2 這樣啦
but right now I don't have dating yet lah
但我現在還沒做到啦
because I'm only touch baby
因為我才剛開始摸索而已啦
so actually I just
所以其實我只是
redefine what is the requirement that I
重新定義我要的需求是什麼
what I want to do then what is the region
我要做什麼，然後 region 是什麼
what is the resource that I want inside there
我要的 resource 是什麼
what is the expected result and also the documentation
預期結果是什麼，還有 documentation
ah this so
啊，這個，所以
maybe I can demo on this so like see how it works
也許我可以 demo 一下，看看它怎樣運作
so basically we just
所以基本上我們就
I just copy this one and then I try to paste here
我把這個複製，然後貼到這裡
so maybe there's
所以可能這裡
I mention here this is the requirement 3
我這裡寫說，這是 requirement 3
for example then I want to create subnet
比如說，然後我要建立 subnet
also I want to create one subnet is VPC itself
我也要建立一個 subnet，就是 VPC 本身
VPC is the virtual network Lah
VPC 就是 virtual network 啦
so is some kind of address range for the
就是某種地址範圍，給那個
for the environment itself
給 environment 本身
so we can create a different subnet inside there
所以我們可以在裡面建立不同的 subnet
so for maybe inside this VPC
所以比如在這個 VPC 裡面
I want to create one is called 3 stress on the floor
我要建立一個，地址範圍大概是這樣的
the subnet inside there
裡面的 subnet
then expected result is I want to build the new subnet
預期結果就是我要建一個新的 subnet
and then the documentation all this is the same
然後 documentation 這些都一樣
so after this one
所以這個之後
right after I read after I done the requirement
在我讀完、寫好 requirement 之後
so I go to the Codex agent
我就去 Codex agent
because currently I'm using the Codex itself Lah so
因為我現在用的就是 Codex 啦
wait ah one second
等一下啊，等一下
let me check what is where is my Codex ya Codex here
讓我看看我的 Codex 在哪裡，ya，Codex 在這裡
so in the Codex here right
所以在 Codex 這裡
so maybe I just say I have new requirement
所以我可能就說，我有新的 requirement
help me to create it actually is
幫我建立它，其實就是
because you already read the agents markdown
因為你已經讀了 agents markdown
and also the skills markdown
還有 skills markdown
so know what is the behaviour
所以知道行為是什麼
then what is the things that I want lah
然後我要的是什麼啦
so I just try it
所以我就試試看
try this a new requirement help me to create
試這個：我有新 requirement，幫我建立
then I just click then you try to think lah
然後我一點，它就開始思考啦
then you try to working on it oh
然後它就開始處理，哦
sorry ya but actually it will reads every time lah
不好意思 ya，其實它每次都會重新讀啦
so I'm not sure this one
所以我不確定這個
this part maybe I will try to refine it
這部分我可能會再去最佳化它
but it will read every time
但它每次都會讀
so actually
所以其實
it's quite slow compared to Claude and also the
跟 Claude 比起來它蠻慢的，還有那個
also the Cursor AI and so on ya
還有 Cursor AI 那些，ya
so it knows the requirement 3 is the new ya correct
所以它知道 requirement 3 是新的，ya，沒錯
so ya so you will see
所以 ya，你會看到
so you will read down all the IaC
它會把所有 IaC 都讀一遍
then see what is the new requirement
然後看新的 requirement 是什麼
because when we create those
因為當我們建立那些
requirement 1 and requirement 2
requirement 1 和 requirement 2
all the code it will generate as a code inside there
所有程式碼它都會生成在裡面
so you will read out all the codes
所以它會把所有程式碼讀出來
see what is the things that missing in the requirement
看看 requirement 裡缺了什麼
so you will see there is a requirement 3
所以你會看到有一個 requirement 3
another subnet so we will try to
另一個 subnet，所以我們會去
update the network modules
更新 network modules
or all those code inside there
或者裡面那些程式碼
so I not need to care
所以我不需要去管
like what is the code inside there
裡面的程式碼是什麼
because before this before this AI and so also yeah
因為在這之前，在有 AI 之前，yeah
before this AI actually I refer to the I
在有 AI 之前，其實我要去參考那個 IaC
a C document one by one to see like for example
文件，一個一個去看，比如說
because a G a G
因為那個
O AWS have a lot of the resources
AWS 有很多 resources
then their resources have
然後它們的 resources 有
is specific things that you need to mention
有些特定的東西你需要去寫明
when you create the code so I need to refer the code
當你寫程式碼的時候，所以我需要去參考
the documentation
那個文件
one by one to see what is the code that I need to
一個一個去看，我需要寫什麼程式碼
include inside there so actually if using AI
要放在裡面，所以其實如果用 AI
I don't need to care because it will automatically
我就不用管，因為它會自動
generate all the codes itself
自己生成所有程式碼
but actually quite slow
但其實蠻慢的
because you need to like see what is the code changes
因為你需要去看程式碼改了什麼
then verify all the things after you generate the code
生成程式碼之後，還要去驗證所有東西
ya then you will to validate the things
ya，然後你要去 validate 那些東西
then I just say yes
然後我就說 yes
then you will validate all the things for me yeah
然後它就幫我 validate 所有東西，yeah
then I just use Terraform
然後我就用 Terraform
plan to see what is the things that I will create
plan 去看我會建立什麼東西
because basically this part is
因為基本上這部分就是
just want to see whether anything that is happen
想看看有沒有發生什麼
any error inside there then it will fix
裡面有沒有 error，然後它會修
so currently it doesn't have any things ah
所以目前沒有什麼問題啊
so you can see there is a result there to say that the
所以你可以看到有個結果在那邊說
after you run the Terraform plan right
在你跑完 Terraform plan 之後
so it will say there is a one thing to add
它會說有一樣東西要加
which is this subnet so it will say Lah
就是這個 subnet，它會這樣說啦
because I just ask him to like not to run this apply
因為我叫它不要去跑這個 apply
because after you run this
因為你一跑這個
it will directly deploy so
它就會直接部署，所以
you will mess up all the things
你會把所有東西搞亂
so I have specifically say
所以我特別交代說
you don't need to terraform apply
你不用去 terraform apply
just plan it and show me ya
只要 plan 然後給我看就好，ya
so after this right
所以這之後
so actually
所以其實
if it goes here right then maybe
如果到這裡，那也許
ancillary ah I didn't met that
其實啊，我沒有遇到那個
I didn't met that issue lah
我沒有遇到那個問題啦
because I have specifically
因為我特別
I mentioned inside the agent.md lah
我在 agent.md 裡寫了啦
markdown file lah ya
就是那個 markdown 檔案啦，ya
you must do this Lor if not
你一定要這樣做咯，不然
then later it will say oh
不然等下它會說，哦
I apply this then mess up everything yeah
我 apply 了這個，然後把全部都搞亂，yeah
mess up whole
搞亂整個
environment actually
其實是整個 environment
so actually I trying to avoid that lah and then if like
所以其實我想避免這個啦，然後如果
let's say I try to run this again
比如說我再跑一次這個
then we will see what is the things that it will add
那我們會看到它會加什麼東西
if let's say I try to apply after plan
假設我 plan 之後去 apply
then we using this command to apply so it will generate
我們用這個 command 去 apply，它就會生成
so it will creating all this subnet inside the AWS
它會在 AWS 裡建立這整個 subnet
so if I come to the AWS right
所以如果我去到 AWS
so it will refresh this so eventually ya
它會重新整理這個，所以最終 ya
you can see there is a requirement 3 subnet here
你可以看到這裡有一個 requirement 3 subnet
there is already created inside the aw
已經在 AWS 裡建立好了
oh sorry
哦，不好意思
it will create inside the AWS already
它已經在 AWS 裡建立好了
which is a requirement 3 subnet here
就是這裡的 requirement 3 subnet
oh sorry
哦，不好意思
subnet yeah
subnet，yeah
so that is a subnet lah it's already creating yeah
所以那是一個 subnet 啦，已經建立好了，yeah
so actually
所以其實
I'm trying to integrate all the things from there lah
我想把那邊所有東西整合起來啦
like how does it work with the infrastructure
就是它怎樣跟 infrastructure 一起運作
so actually yeah
所以其實，yeah
this is the things the
這就是那個
this is the end to end workflow Lah for my
這就是端到端的 workflow 啦，給我的
for my POC of this
給我這個 POC
AI integration with the AI yeah
AI 整合的 POC，yeah
so
所以
it's very simple you just write down the requirements
其實很簡單，你只要把需求寫下來
then agent read agent update the IaC
然後 agent 讀、agent 更新 IaC
run all the validation then we can
跑完所有 validation，然後我們就可以
but this part I haven't do it lah
但這部分我還沒做啦
because this part is involve of the CI/CD
因為這部分牽涉到 CI/CD
actually I
其實我
this is my next step lah to develop the CI/CD for this
這是我的下一步啦，去開發這個的 CI/CD
so the AI can help to pull request
這樣 AI 可以幫忙做 pull request
then our human side will be the one who approve it
然後我們人這邊就是負責審批的
and so on to review all the
等等，去 review 所有
whole then only the CI/CD
整個，然後才是 CI/CD
then after we approve
然後我們審批之後
then only the CI/CD will do the code
才會由 CI/CD 去做程式碼
deployment to the Github then the Github there will
部署到 GitHub，然後 GitHub 那邊會
we will run the pipeline to deploy
我們會跑 pipeline 去部署
to use the Terraform apply
用 Terraform apply
to directly deploy the resources inside the
直接把 resources 部署到
environment itself ya
environment 裡面，ya
this involves the CI/CD part and I'm working on it
這牽涉到 CI/CD 那部分，我正在做
this is my next plan for the CI/CD part Lah so
這是我對 CI/CD 那部分的下一個計劃啦
this is the house the traditional method
這就是傳統的做法
VS the AI assistant method Lah
對比 AI assistant 的做法啦
so basically it's really clear
所以基本上很清楚
it depends on the requirements
就看需求
we can capture it clearly in the markdown file
我們可以在 markdown 檔案裡清楚地記錄下來
and the IaC actually
而 IaC 方面其實
we can just ask the agent to draft code
我們可以直接叫 agent 去起草程式碼
instead of manual coding by the engineer itself so
而不是工程師自己手動寫程式碼
in this part right
在這部分
so we are working as a cloud architect for example
所以我們就像是 cloud architect 那樣，比如說
I'm only to think what to design
我只需要去想要設計什麼
what resources they need to use
需要用什麼 resources
then design all the architecture
然後設計整個 architecture
then after that I design all the solution already
然後我設計好整個方案之後
then I just ask the agent I want this resources
我就叫 agent 說，我要這些 resources
help me to create it ya that's the things ah
幫我建立，ya，就是這樣啊
so we are act as a cloud architect already and
所以我們已經是扮演 cloud architect 的角色，而且
from the AI assistant we will have a human review
用 AI assistant 的話，我們會有 human review
and also the automated analysis
還有自動化的分析
has to see what the code review
去看那個 code review
what is your
你的是什麼
issue inside the code and so on then for the speed
程式碼裡有什麼問題等等，然後講到速度
basically ah
基本上啊
it's a faster iteration and the knowledge sharing
迭代更快，還有知識共享
simple lah we can documented repeat
很簡單啦，我們可以記錄下來、可重複
repetable and easier on boarding on the user
可重複，而且更容易讓使用者上手
instead of dependent on the individual expertise
而不是依賴個人的專業經驗
for it since we are asking the agent
因為我們是叫 agent
help us to do the documentation
幫我們做 documentation
so yeah I think that's all for me ah
所以 yeah，我想我就講到這裡啊
actually it's quite short
其實蠻短的
just my proof of concept on how this AI
只是我的 proof of concept，關於這個 AI 怎樣
can be integrated with the infrastructure ya
可以跟 infrastructure 整合，ya
the cloud services ah
就是 cloud services 啊
for ya so actually I just want to show
ya，其實我只是想展示
there's also the architecture man the
還有那個 architecture，那個
air markdown
就是那個畫流程圖的 markdown
so you can see what is the flowchart in here and so on
所以你可以看到這裡的流程圖等等
this is like for example
這個比如說
if let's say you want to hand over to the next person
假設你要交接給下一個人
then the next person know how to use this
那下一個人就知道怎樣用這個
Terraform to deploy the resources and so on
用 Terraform 去部署 resources 等等
maybe because some of the engineer
因為也許有些工程師
they don't have cloud engineer
他們沒有 cloud engineer 的背景
they don't have the I C back background ya
他們沒有 IaC 的背景，ya
so they can refer to this then see what is
所以他們可以參考這個，然後看看
what can he do lah to deploy the resources inside there
他可以怎樣去部署裡面的 resources 啦
ya
ya
any questions okay
有什麼問題嗎，okay
thank you for the talk
謝謝你的分享
okay my
okay，我的
first I verify
首先我確認一下
what I understand from the
我從這裡理解到的
this workflow lah basically when you prompt it like
這個 workflow 啦，基本上當你 prompt 它的時候
just now you prompt like I have new requirements
就像你剛才 prompt 說，我有新的 requirements
please help me to implement it right
請幫我實現它，對吧
so what the AI will basically do is like
所以 AI 基本上會做的就是
to read the requirement.md
去讀 requirement.md
and then see
然後看
the new requirement over there
那邊新的 requirement
and then integrate it into the IaC file in the
然後把它整合進 IaC 檔案，就是
Terraform file that you have
你那個 Terraform 檔案
like define over there right
就是你在那邊定義的，對吧
correct alright
對，好
oh okay
哦，okay
so
那麼
let's say if let's is there like cases where like
比如說，有沒有那種情況是
you have existing requirement already
你已經有現有的 requirement
that is already deploy
已經部署了的
live on the Azure
在 Azure 上 live 執行的
platform over there and maybe then suddenly
在那個平臺上，然後可能突然
maybe the company something
可能公司有什麼
you got new requirement or something
你有新的 requirement 之類的
existing deployment has to be like
現有的 deployment 需要
updated or something like that
被更新之類的
like change this subnet or maybe add new sub server
比如改這個 subnet，或者加新的 server
close that server something like that in that case
關掉那個 server 之類的，那種情況下
we'll we'll we'll such a scenario happen
會，會，會發生這種情況
ya actually it will have so for Terraform
ya，其實會有的，因為 Terraform
how it read the current state right
它怎樣讀取當前的 state 呢
so there is a file called terraform.tfstate
有一個檔案叫 terraform.tfstate
so
所以
this state is actually something like a caching for
這個 state 其實有點像一個 cache（快取）
of your current the existing project
快取你當前現有的 project
set up so for example
的設定，比如說
if let's say previously my requirement
假設之前我的 requirement
I have two subnet set up using this Terraform right
我用這個 Terraform 設了兩個 subnet
so after you deploy using this terraform
所以你用這個 terraform 部署之後
it will actually store the state inside the tfstate so
它其實會把 state 存到 tfstate 裡面
how
那麼
so after that if I let's say
之後假設我
I have a new requirement to create one more subnet
我有新的 requirement 要多建立一個 subnet
inside there so actually
在裡面，其實
it will read the current setup using this tfstate
它會用這個 tfstate 去讀取當前的設定
first to see what is the currently already set up
先看目前已經設好了什麼
then to define this is the new requirement for that
然後定義說，這是新的 requirement
so those things are doing during the terraform plan ah
所以這些都是在 terraform plan 的時候做的啊
so after you run the terraform plan right
所以你跑完 terraform plan 之後
so you can see they will tell you what is
你可以看到它會告訴你
the things that will be created so
會建立什麼東西，所以
those existing things
那些現有的東西
they will not be recreated again oh ya
它們不會被重新建立，哦 ya
so if let's say I want to delete one subnet from there
所以假設我要從那邊刪掉一個 subnet
I just delete the code from the Terraform
我只要把 Terraform 裡的程式碼刪掉
the Terraform code after I deleting right
就是 Terraform code，我刪了之後
so after I run this Terraform plan
我跑這個 Terraform plan 之後
it will read something's missing from the code
它會讀到程式碼裡少了東西
so it will consider this as a destroy
所以它會把這個當作 destroy（銷燬）
so after you run the Terraform plan
所以你跑完 Terraform plan 之後
it will mention here the
它會在這裡提到
there is one subnet will be destroy so this
有一個 subnet 會被 destroy，所以這個
so the destroy resources is the resources
所以 destroy 的 resources 就是那些
they will delete from the environment itself ya
會從 environment 裡刪掉的 resources，ya
so we don't simply change the code inside
所以我們不能隨便去改裡面的程式碼
the Terraform code also lah
就是 Terraform code 啦
so if let's say I deleting this right
所以假設我刪掉這個
means I already
意思是我已經
I want to delete this resources from the environment ya
我要從 environment 刪掉這些 resources，ya
this is how Terraform to define lah
Terraform 就是這樣定義的啦
what is the resources will be delete
哪些 resources 會被刪掉
ya so is this answer your question
ya，這樣有回答到你的問題嗎
yeah answer my question okay
yeah，有回答到，okay
so because just now ah
所以因為剛才啊
my first question is actually like
我第一個問題其實是
I'm curious lah like
我很好奇啦
if let's say I just go into the requirement.md
假設我直接進去 requirement.md
and then I just change the requirement too
然後我去改那個 requirement
maybe
可能
delete some of the something maybe
刪掉一些東西，可能
like add a new server something like that then my
比如加一個新的 server 之類的，那我的
curiosity is like how the AI agent will actually no
好奇就是，AI agent 實際上要怎樣知道
ah what is the difference between the previous one
啊，之前那個跟
and the current one ah
現在這個有什麼不同啊
so your answer just now
所以你剛才的回答
is basically that is a state file that is
基本上就是說，有一個 state file
being stored over there right
存在那邊，對吧
yeah correct
yeah，沒錯
oh bigger
哦，還有
maybe also one 1
也許還有一個
one idea that I come out also Lah is like because
我也想到一個點子啦，就是因為
maybe in the future when I got
也許將來當我
modify the requirement.md
修改 requirement.md
something like that then maybe it can
之類的，那也許它可以
it you
它，你
inside the agent instruction file
在 agent 的指令檔案裡
like the CLAUDE.md maybe
比如 CLAUDE.md
or the agent.md ah
或者 agent.md 啊
maybe also can tell it
也許也可以告訴它
to compare it with the different commit oh
去跟不同的 commit 做對比，哦
I see yes
原來如此，對
correct
沒錯
yeah you can compare it with the different the
yeah，你可以拿它跟不同的
previous commit it can perform a git difference
之前的 commit 做對比，它可以執行 git difference（git diff）
and then you can see basically
然後你基本上就可以看到
or what
或者
line do you change and something like that
你改了哪一行之類的
then also combine with the terraform state file
然後再結合 terraform state file
and then you can get a clear picture of I
這樣你就可以更清楚地看到，我
see okay
原來如此，okay
what it can be wait
它可以是，等一下
what it can be like
它可以是
update lah I see okay
更新啦，原來如此，okay
ya
ya
thanks for the advice ya
謝謝你的建議，ya
this one actually good advice
這個其實是很好的建議
I will take it ya
我會採納的，ya
yeah
yeah
because just now I see oh
因為剛才我看到，哦
I think that kind one can also be done yeah
我覺得那種也是可以做到的，yeah
because sometimes they will just change the requirement
因為有時候他們會直接改 requirement
do all the things then you need to compare
做一堆東西，然後你就需要去對比
see what is the thing already change yeah
看看什麼東西已經改了，yeah
actually good advice from that yes
其實那是很好的建議，yes
also additionally like
另外補充一下
when like tell it to implement something
就是當你叫它去實現某個東西的時候
maybe also can make it
也許也可以讓它
so that it come up with a plan first
先想出一個 plan
k maybe because those changes even
k，因為那些改動，即使
if one line that can be
只是一行，也可能
also be a large change to the whole infrastructure
對整個 infrastructure 造成很大的改變
right yeah
對吧，yeah
correct
沒錯
maybe
也許
can also tell the agent to like
也可以叫 agent
first come up with a plan
先想出一個 plan
and then also the agent should car
然後 agent 也應該
also give a reasoning in detail
也要給出詳細的推理
like why do you change why the agent change this code
比如為什麼要改，為什麼 agent 改了這段程式碼
what is the reasoning behind that like
背後的理由是什麼
it can map from your requirement to the
它可以從你的 requirement 對應到
to the actual changes that it have done lah
它實際做的那些改動啦
and then at the end we
然後到最後我們
are we as like the engineer
我們作為工程師
we go through the requirements
我們過一遍那些 requirements
the plan that it give Lah
還有它給的那個 plan 啦
and then we approve it
然後我們批准它
and then only then you go implement the plan
然後才去執行那個 plan
okay
okay
can yeah
可以，yeah
that's my 2 cents ah for this okay
這是我對這個的一點意見啊，okay
can ya thank you
可以 ya，謝謝
thank you thank you
謝謝，謝謝
thank you thank you for that
謝謝，謝謝你的意見
any more question okay
還有問題嗎，okay
I give you a question so far like your project
我問你一個問題，到目前為止，關於你的 project
I mean like for your real have
我是說，你有沒有真的
you started for use it in real project
開始把它用在真實的 project 上
actually don't have yet because my current company they
其實還沒有，因為我現在的公司他們
wanted to put this
想把這個
things the
東西
this one in the next contract
這個放在下一個合約裡
actually the my project next contract Lah
其實是我 project 的下一個合約啦
so actually by right this year
所以照理說今年
we need to start on this IaC things
我們就要開始做這個 IaC 的東西
but because from scratch
但因為是從零開始
when you doing this from scratch
當你從零開始做這個
it's very easy because you are
其實很容易，因為你
you are doing this from the scratch
你是從零開始做
then you are the pure new tfstate file
那你就是一個全新的 tfstate file
so this one tfstate file is like something like a cache
所以這個 tfstate file 有點像一個 cache
you will know what is your current set out and so on
你會知道你當前的設定等等
so let's say I we
所以假設我，我們
I want to import the existing
我要匯入現有的
resources inside this Terraform files right
resources 到這個 Terraform 檔案裡
it's very hard it's very difficult for us to do it
那就很難，對我們來說很難做到
so eventually they want to put it in the
所以最終他們想把它放在
next project contract Lah yeah
下一個 project 合約裡啦，yeah
it will takes time to do it
這需要時間去做
so maybe we will wait for your next NPS
所以也許我們要等你下一次咯
this one
這個
this one is quite hard Lah
這個蠻難的啦
but for that all small project right
但對於那些小 project
actually it will deploy to my own environment in here
其實它會部署到我自己的 environment 這裡
so actually I trying to complete all the whole floors
所以其實我想把整個流程都跑完
then I only can present lah
然後我才能展示啦
what is the thing that I because I trying to actually
我做的東西，因為我其實想
I also got do the MCP server for myself
我自己也有做一個 MCP server
just now I asking Jun Wei about
剛才我問 Jun Wei 關於
because I also got
因為我也有
do the AI budget tracking software itself
做一個 AI budget tracking 的軟體
so actually I want to do the whole 4
所以其實我想做整個流程
from the developer code itself
從 developer 寫程式碼本身
until the CICD
一直到 CI/CD
then until the hosting the infrastructure itself
然後到 host infrastructure 本身
buying the domain host
買 domain、host
the ssl certificate and so on
SSL certificate 等等
so I want to do the whole flow to represent my
所以我想做整個流程，來代表我的
portfolio lah as my portfolio
portfolio 啦，當作我的作品集
when I trying to do finding the next job
當我要找下一份工作的時候
then I will say that
我就可以說
I have one portfolio that design by myself
我有一個自己設計的 portfolio
all the solution that design by myself yeah
所有方案都是我自己設計的，yeah
just ask only if I can answer then I answer
儘管問，如果我答得到我就答
[in Mandarin] Yes, what you presented
是的，你剛才發表的
is basically right, but there are a few points I think you could improve.
基本上是對的，但有幾個點我覺得你可以改進。
One thing — in your company, you should pay
第一個，在你公司裡，你要
attention to how your agents are set up. Looking at your
注意你的 agents 是怎樣設定的。看你的
workflow, you've got several workflows, so I think
workflow，你有好幾個 workflow，所以我覺得
you could split that agent — the Codex agent you mentioned — and then have another
你可以把那個 agent 分開——你說的那個 Codex agent——然後再用另一個
one handle something else. Yeah, yeah. So that's the first
去處理別的東西。Yeah，yeah。這是第一
point. Second point: your requirement — you could actually turn it into a
點。第二點：你的 requirement，其實你可以把它變成一個
reference. Basically,
reference（參考）。基本上，
you could write it as an example. Then
你可以把它寫成一個 example。然後
when you have more agents, you can tell them to follow that example and
當你有更多 agents 的時候，你可以叫它們照著那個 example，去
come ask you for the information, instead of writing everything in one place. Ya
來跟你要那些 information，而不是把全部都寫在一個地方。Ya
ya
ya
When an engineer comes on board, they can also refer to this —
當有工程師加入的時候，他們也可以參考這個——
hand over the docs to see, like,
就是交接文件，去看看
how he should run this code, and also
他要怎樣跑這些程式碼，還有
how to run these things, and how he brings in his
怎樣跑這些東西，還有他要怎樣把他的
requirements, and what that looks like.
requirement 放進來，是什麼樣子的。
So does your agent's context hold all the skills? Oh, is it your
所以你 agent 的背景裡有全部的 skill 嗎？哦，是不是你的
agent's context that says who uses which skill, which skill
agent 背景裡寫說，誰用哪個 skill、用哪個 skill
is used and how much — it's all here, lah. But I'd want to separate them, but
用多少——全部都在這裡啦。但我會想把它們分開，但
because this is the first one I did. I myself, basically,
因為這是我做的第一個。我自己，基本上
built it from scratch, so I haven't gone into this much detail yet, because
從零開始做出來，所以還沒做到這麼細，因為
I need time to
我需要時間去
differentiate requirements and also the skills, ah
區分 requirements 和 skills，啊
so skills Kena I will be based on the
所以 skills 嘛，我會根據
skills I will be function Kena VM skills network skills
skills 按功能去分，像 VM skills、network skills
Then inside network skills I'll define, like,
然後在 network skills 裡面，我會定義，比如
if you want to create that network, what you need to do; and
如果你要建立那個 network，你需要怎樣做；還有
if you want to create this VM, what you need to do, because
如果你要建立這個 VM，你需要怎樣做，因為
different resources inside the cloud
cloud 裡面不同的 resources
they will different the requirements from there
它們的需求是不一樣的
yeah so I will
yeah，所以我會
find skills like VM and those, lah — requirement is the same too.
定義像 VM 那些的 skills 啦——requirement 也是一樣的。
like, say, requirement skills, right — I'd also split it, maybe into
比如說 requirement skills，對吧——我也會把它分開，可能分成
what the VM requirement is,
VM 的 requirement 是什麼，
and what my
還有我的
network requirement is.
network requirement 是什麼。
Like that, lah — I'll split it up this way. This is something I
就這樣啦——我會這樣去分。這個是我
made myself — a simple markdown, lah, for POC only.
自己做的——一個簡單的 markdown 啦，只是給 POC 用的。
yeah, because I just want to show, like, how
yeah，因為我只是想展示，就是
this AI — this markdown thing — can integrate with
這個 AI，這個 markdown 的東西，可以怎樣整合
Cloud Services ah AWS Azure Ya
Cloud Services 啊，AWS、Azure，Ya
Chinese or English
要中文還是英文
ah English ah okay
啊，英文啊，okay
so to confirm again ah those
那我再確認一下啊，那些
when you ask the agent to like do some changes
當你叫 agent 去做一些改動
to the requirements whether if it's a new requirements
對那些 requirements，不管是新的 requirements
or a update to the requirements right it price
還是更新現有的 requirements，對吧
it will go and modify the Terraform file itself
它會去修改 Terraform 檔案本身
and then from
然後從
what you said like each of the configuration
你說的，每一個 configuration
there is very strict right like the setting and
都很嚴格，對吧，就是那些設定，還有
the parameter and everything
parameter 等等所有東西
must be like confirmed to the documentation
都必須符合 documentation
and the actual website
還有實際的網站
so right now the agent got like
所以現在 agent 有沒有
before you do the modification
在你做修改之前
does it like have a step to go to the website
它有沒有一個步驟去那個網站
see the official documentation and then confirm oh
看官方的 documentation，然後確認，哦
this parameter can be used oh
這個 parameter 可以用，哦
that one
那個
so that the agent actually don't actually hallucinate
這樣 agent 才不會亂產生幻覺（hallucinate）
what is the parameter that
就是那個 parameter
it will just insert into the code where
它會直接插進程式碼裡，那
which if let's say there is a lot of modification
假設有很多改動的話
maybe we have a problem spotting it
也許我們很難發現它
and then just do the
然後就直接
oil or something oh
之類的，哦
actually that part I was
其實那部分我是
I actually I was trusting the agent
我其實是信任 agent 的
the agent itself already have a letter latest
agent 本身已經有最新的
version read the latest documentation from the
版本，會去讀最新的 documentation，從那個
like for example
比如說
the AWS website or the Azure website itself
AWS 的網站或 Azure 的網站
so
所以
actually I'm trusting the agent for it lah but
其實這方面我是信任 agent 的啦，但
if let's say there is a issue
假設有問題的話
because maybe sometimes the things happen
因為有時候會發生一些狀況
some requirement is changing right
有些 requirement 會改變，對吧
so the code itself have a issue
所以程式碼本身有問題
when they're defining this requirement
當它在定義這個 requirement 的時候
so actually I think the because in the last step
所以其實我想，因為在最後一步
the agent will verify will validate the code
agent 會去 verify、validate 那個程式碼
will verify the code
會驗證程式碼
and then do run the Terraform plan
然後去跑 Terraform plan
if actually there is a
如果其實有
something happen inside the Terraform code itself right
Terraform code 本身出了什麼狀況
the Terraform plan will also fail
那 Terraform plan 也會失敗
ya it will fail the command ya
ya，那個 command 會失敗，ya
it will prompt say that oh
它會提示說，哦
this one is the outdated or something lah ya that one
這個過時了之類的啦，ya，那個
yeah
yeah
so the a so
所以那個，所以
the agent itself will can
agent 本身就可以
be that identify from there lah
從那邊識別出來啦
I see maybe what my in is because
原來如此，也許我的意思是
in my opinion lah
在我看來啦
maybe it can integrate with a workflow that
也許它可以整合一個 workflow
before performing any
在執行任何
update to like the Terraform file eh
對 Terraform 檔案的更新之前，eh
add a step
加一個步驟
maybe it will go and check the official documentation
也許它會去查官方的 documentation
and then have you heard of the
然後，你有沒有聽過那個
one of the skill is called Context7
其中一個 skill 叫 Context7
context 7 is actually a skill that
Context7 其實是一個 skill
because we are right now to modify like
因為我們現在要修改的，像
what whether it is like Terraform or maybe like
不管是 Terraform 還是
typescript or any programming language or any library
TypeScript，或者任何程式語言、任何 library
we are trusting the AI to basically know like
我們是相信 AI 基本上會知道
or the
或者那個
it knows the official documentation of the latest right
它知道最新的官方 documentation，對吧
but let's say is suddenly one day the
但假設突然有一天那個
library got some breaking changes
library 有一些 breaking changes
or something like that
之類的
then the agent wouldn't really know it if very lucky it
那 agent 其實不太會知道，如果很幸運的話它
will go and check and then see the latest changes
會去查，然後看到最新的改動
Lah but then actually
啦，但其實
let's say for that case lah
假設那種情況啦
it got the library got some frequent changes
如果那個 library 經常有改動
then that one actually we
那種情況其實我們
got a library call
有一個 library 叫
not library the skill lah call Context7
不是 library，是那個 skill 啦，叫 Context7
they just call it a Context7 ah
他們就叫它 Context7 啊
which is a skill you can install to the agents
它是一個你可以安裝到 agents 上的 skill
and then basically if you NPS
然後基本上如果你裝上它
add a step lah to it
給它加一個步驟啦
is more it
就比較
got the MCP
它有 MCP
and also got the skill and then it basically can like
也有那個 skill，然後它基本上就可以
go
去
and like
就
always check the official documentation
一直去查官方的 documentation
it is like more like its own setup kind of thing that
它比較像是它自己的一套設定，就是
like say or I want to change this Terraform
比如說我要改這個 Terraform
then maybe you will go and search for the Context7
那也許你會去搜 Context7
and then pull the latest documentation
然後拉取最新的 documentation
and then it will know or how to
然後它就會知道要怎樣
how to like do the changes
怎樣去做那些改動
I see okay
原來如此，okay
can
可以
just my 2 cents on that Lah okay
這只是我的一點意見啦，okay
can thank you okay
可以，謝謝，okay
thank you thank you
謝謝，謝謝
thank you for the advice okay
謝謝你的建議，okay
I have one but it is not related to AI Lah
我有一個問題，但它跟 AI 沒關係啦
it is more related to Terraform Lah
它比較跟 Terraform 有關啦
because I notice there's a wording
因為我注意到有個字眼
the costing Lah just as for
就是成本啦，作為
cloud engineer the
cloud engineer 來說
most important thing to consider is costing ah
最重要要考慮的就是成本啊
so for costing wise
所以在成本方面
how can it helps ah
它怎樣幫得上忙啊
by using Terraform
用 Terraform 的話
actually Terraform doesn't help on the costing itself
其實 Terraform 本身不會幫到成本這塊
for example
比如說
because when we trying to write the requirement
因為當我們要寫 requirement 的時候
before we writing the requirement
在我們寫 requirement 之前
actually we have a step
其實我們有一個步驟
like
就是
to define what is the resources that we need to use
去定義我們需要用什麼 resources
first we will design the architecture
首先我們會設計 architecture
first to see what is the resources that we use
先看我們用什麼 resources
then secondly
然後第二
we will see what is the specification that we need
我們會看我們需要什麼規格
to use like for example the VM itself
比如說 VM 本身
we want to use four CPU core and also the 16 gig RAM
我們要用四個 CPU core，還有 16 gig 的 RAM
then we will find the instance size for it
然後我們會去找適合的 instance size
after we gather all the requirement
在我們收集完所有 requirement 之後
all the
所有的
we then we specify all the things already right
我們把所有東西都指定好了之後
then we will check what is the costing of that so
然後我們會去查那個的成本，所以
for example this is some
比如說這是一些
extra knowledge for it lah so for example
額外的知識啦，比如說
how do I calculate the costing
我要怎樣計算成本
is using one thing is called pricing calculator
是用一個叫 pricing calculator 的東西
there is a agent itself
它本身就有一個
there is a pricing calculator for it so actually
它有一個 pricing calculator，所以其實
like for example if let's say I want to add the VM
比如說，假設我要加一臺 VM
then we I just add the VM in here right
那我就把 VM 加在這裡
where is the VM ya add the VM in here
VM 在哪裡，ya，把 VM 加在這裡
then I specify Lor like what is the
然後我就指定咯，比如說
what is the region I want and so on
我要的 region 是什麼等等
then the Windows or Linux here
然後是 Windows 還是 Linux
then after that right when you go scroll down here
然後之後，當你往下滾動到這裡
you can see there's a instance here
你可以看到這裡有個 instance
so what do I want to use after that
然後我要用哪個
then I will show what is the costing for per month
它就會顯示每個月的成本是多少
then we will base on this costing to see what
然後我們就根據這個成本去看
is the total cost
總成本是多少
for the whole environment itself ah
整個 environment 的總成本啊
so for the whole environment itself
所以對整個 environment 來說
there is a pay as you go Lah pay
有一種是 pay as you go 啦
this is the basic one is a pay as you go
這是最基本的，就是 pay as you go
but if let's say I already I
但假設我已經
already
已經
expect this server will be hosting as a long term plan
預計這臺 server 會長期 host 下去
5 years like 10 years and so on
5 年、10 年之類的
so
那麼
I can actually buy the reserve reservation Lah for it
我其實可以為它買 reservation（預留）啦
so actually the reservation
所以其實那個 reservation
if you have some discount Lah
會有一些折扣啦
the agent itself have a
它本身有
some discount for this long term plan and so on eh
對這種長期方案有一些折扣等等，eh
ya never mind it's okay so for example
ya，沒關係，okay，比如說
if you have 21 $21 only compared to like if you use
如果你只要 21，才 21 令吉，相比之下如果你用
let's say you use pay as you go per month
假設你用 pay as you go，按月算
it was 65 ringgit so this one is
就要 65 令吉，所以這個是
for the long term plan Lah like for example
給長期方案用的啦，比如說
let's say you have 3 years 5 years
假設你有 3 年、5 年
you need to use this plan
你需要用這個方案
then you can just buy the reservation for it Lah ya
那你就可以直接買 reservation 啦，ya
but this reservation is actually buying for like
但這個 reservation 其實是一次過買
you totally just buy for 3 years
你是整整買 3 年
instead of you paying it one by
而不是你一次
one day by Monday ya
一天一天那樣付，ya
this is a
這是一個
some extra knowledge on the cloud services itself lah
關於 cloud services 的一些額外知識啦
oh means basically after you know the numbers
哦，意思是基本上你知道那些數字之後
then you directly state in the Terraform
你就直接寫在 Terraform 裡
ya stay inside the Terraform
ya，放在 Terraform 裡面
then stay inside just now the requirement markdown say
然後放在剛才那個 requirement markdown 裡，說
oh I want this instance
哦，我要這個 instance
then how what is the specification
然後規格是什麼
what is the instance size I want
我要的 instance size 是什麼
then what is the thing that I want
然後我要的是什麼
then I specify inside the requirement
我就寫在 requirement 裡面
then it will help me to generate the code for it lor
然後它就會幫我生成程式碼咯
so basically it is
所以基本上就是
the Terraform will be the execution
Terraform 是負責執行的部分
there is a workflow
有一個 workflow
it will place as a execution lah instead of planning
它是放在執行的部分啦，而不是規劃
so the costing the specification
所以成本、規格
all this is doing this during the planning part
這些都是在規劃階段做的
instead of the execution part Lah
而不是執行階段啦
so Terraform and also the AI
所以 Terraform 還有 AI
all these it just help me on the execution part
這些都只是幫我處理執行的部分
so all these I
所以這些我
all these still we need to think what is the solution
這些我們還是要自己想方案是什麼
then how to define what is the costing
然後怎樣定義成本
then what is the best costing option for the client
然後對客戶來說最划算的方案是什麼
oh there
哦，那
is one question ah
有一個問題啊
NPS regarding to architecture
關於 architecture，
have you ever
你有沒有試過
use AI to like
用 AI 去
provide some idea lah on
給一些點子啦，關於
some sort of architecture that you
某種 architecture，你
not really actually
其實沒有
but I not sure how AI can integrated
但我不確定 AI 要怎樣整合
for example the draw Io and also the lucid chart
比如說 draw.io 還有 Lucidchart
maybe
也許
there is a AI already integrated in the lucid chart
Lucidchart 裡面可能已經整合了 AI
but I didn't use it before lah
但我之前沒用過啦
so maybe next time I can use it
所以也許下次我可以用
for the architecture part Lah
用在 architecture 那部分啦
like using the lucidchart
就是用 Lucidchart
maybe there is a built in AI
也許它有內建的 AI
then I just say I want what things
然後我只要說我要什麼東西
then it will help me to
然後它就會幫我
generate the architecture
生成 architecture
this one I can explore maybe after that
這個我可以之後再去探索
so ya
所以 ya
but for currently I don't use it
但目前我沒有用
any other question no
還有其他問題嗎，沒有
okay thank you
okay，謝謝
thank you thank you so much
謝謝，非常感謝